insideretail.com.au 2019-08-08

# Privacy Policy & Cookies | Octomedia - Serving Audiences in Australia and the World since 1972

**The following document sets forth the Privacy Policy & Cookies for the Octomedia website, [www.octomedia.com.au](http://www.octomedia.com.au/)**

Octomedia is committed to providing you with the best possible customer service experience. Octomedia is bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Crh), which sets out a number of principles concerning the privacy of individuals. The data protection and privacy of our customers and site visitors are of high importance for Octomedia. Octomedia Pty Ltd is an Australian company, however we also adhere to the principles of data processing set out in the European Union’s (EU) General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

**Who is the controller of your personal information?**  
Any personal data submitted to or gathered by Octomedia’s Publications are controlled by Octomedia Pty Ltd, ABN 98 090 664 305, Level 10, 51-57 Pitt Street, Sydney NSW 2000, publisher of: see [current titles here](https://octomedia.com.au/).

**Collection of your personal information**  
There are many aspects of the site which can be viewed without providing personal information, however, for access to Octomedia customer support features you are required to submit personally identifiable information. This may include but is not limited to a unique username and password, or provide sensitive information in the recovery of your lost password or to assist you with any other issues. Additional information is gathered on users to assist content creation and direction, as-well as allowing advertisers, through our opted in channels, the ability to communicate with you.

Our website is not intended for individuals under the age of 16 years old, anyone younger needs the consent of their parent or guardian. We do not deliberately collect any personal data on children under the age of 16. Therefore, if we find that we have inadvertently obtained personal data of such, we will take steps to erase this data as quickly as possible, except when we are legally bound to keep them.

**Sharing of your personal information**  
We may occasionally hire other companies to provide services on our behalf, including but not limited to handling customer support enquiries, processing transactions or customer freight shipping. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service. Octomedia takes reasonable steps to ensure that these organisations are bound by confidentiality and privacy obligations in relation to the protection of your personal information.

**Use of your personal information**  
For each visitor to reach the site, we expressively collect the following non-personally identifiable information, including but not limited to browser type, version and language, operating system, pages viewed while browsing the Site, page access times and referring website address. This collected information is used solely internally for the purpose of gauging visitor traffic, trends and delivering personalized content to you while you are at this Site.

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will use for these new purposes only, data collected from the time of the policy change forward will adhere to our updated practices.

We use the personal information you provide only for purposes consistent with the reason you provided it, or for a directly related purpose. Generally, we will not use your personal information to market to you unless we have either your implied or express consent but in situations where it is impractical to obtain your prior consent, we will ensure you have an ability to opt out of future such communications.

**What are your rights?**  
You have these legal data protection rights under the relevant legal conditions: Right to information, right to access, right to rectification, right to to object to automated processing, right to erasure, right to data portability, right to withdraw consent as well as right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

A rights request can be made by an individual data subject or an individual’s legal representative. You may be required to put your request in writing for security reasons.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
Octomedia reserves the right to make amendments to this Privacy Policy at any time. If you have objections to the Privacy Policy, you should not access or use the Site.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small units of data saved to, and, during subsequent visits, retrieved from your computer or mobile device to enhance your browsing experience. They do not contain any personal data and cannot be used to identify an individual user.

We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. Cookies also allow our website to store your preferences, save your products or collect statistics on user activities in order to provide better, more user-friendly services.

Some of the cookies expire at the end of your website session, others remain stored on your computer. By continuing to browse our sites, you agree to our use of such cookies on your device.  
You can easily erase or disable cookies from your computer or mobile device using your browser.

**Contacting us**  
Octomedia welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy and would like further information, please contact us by any of the following means during business hours Monday to Friday.

**The Privacy Officer**  
** Octomedia Pty Ltd**  
** Level 10, 51-57 Pitt Street NSW 2000**  
** P O Box 2017, Royal Exchange, NSW 1225**  
** Email: privacyofficer@octomedia.com.au  
** Phone: 02 9901 1800**  
** Fax: 02 9251 5957****
